Juncheng (Billy) Li





+1 (412) 999 5427



junchenl@andrew.cmu.edu lijuncheng16@gmail.com



https://junchengbillyli.com

ABOUT ME

"With multi-disciplinary knowledge background and a clear focus on robust deep learning in multi-modal machine learning, I have prepared myself to delve into more challenging research problems, solve them and create something of value to the real-world!"

RESEARCH INTEREST

- # Robust Deep Learning
- # Multimodal Machine Learning
- # Natural language Processing
- # Audio / Speech Processing

Reviewer

ICML 20/21/22, NeurIPS 20/21, ICLR 2022, AAAI 20/21, CVPR 20/21/22, ACL 21/22 IEEE TALLIP, IEEE TNNLS

Teaching

11-751 Speech Recognition; 15-640 Distributed Stystem; Mentoring Undergrads.

Page 1/2

WORK EXPERIENCE -

Quantative Research Consultant

Two Sigma Investment LLC

May 2022 - Present | New York, NY

- Curate evaluations and/or scoring of audio/video/imagery data, particularly those with economic meaning
- ◆ Deep Learning Research Engineer Bosch Center for Artificial Intelligence

Jul 2018 - Sept 2019 | Pittsburgh, PA

- Applied robust machine learning algorithms to Bosch Autonomous driving project, improved system robustness by 50% in bad weather condition.
- Explored mulimodality embeddings to make use of multi-sensor input, transferred the technology to Bosch business team.
- Developed occupancy detection solution using RGB-D sensor, and facilitated the transfer of technology to business unit.
- Applied representation learning to Bosch drier, improved energy efficiency by 5%.
- Generated 2 patents and top-tier AI conference publications.
- Mentored 2 interns and hired 5 members for the new team.
- Research Engineer

Bosch Research and Technology Center

Apr 2015 - June 2018 | Pittsburgh, PA

- Designed, Developed, and tested a 3D visualization platform based on BIM (Building Information Model) for Smart Campus sensor network (MQTT protocol) using Java at backend and Javascript at frontend.
- Collaborated closely with Bosch Next App development team, developed VR indoor navigation solution, and deployed the Bosch Next APP on App Store.
- Applied sound recognition to manufactoring production line to detect potential anomaly thus reducing the overall downtime by 10%.
- Applied sound recognition to detect leak in water pipelines, generated 1 patent.

EDUCATION

PHD Candidate (Language Technology Institute)
 School of Computer Science, Carnegie Mellon University

2017 - Present (expected Dec 2022) | Pittsburgh, PA

Dual Degree Master of Science (Advanced Infrastructure
 System + Engineering Technology Innovation & Management)
 Carnegie Mellon University

2012 - 2015 | Pittsburgh, PA

 Bachelor of Science in Structural Engineering Tongji University

2008 - 2012 | Shanghai, China

Exchange Student in Civil Engineering
 National Chengkung University

2012 | Tainan, Taiwan

COURSE

NLP & Deep Learning

- # Neural Networks for NLP
- # Neural Machine Translation
- # Deep Reinforcement Learning
- # Speech Recognition
- # Algorithm for NLP
- # Large Scale MultiMedia Analysis
- # Machine Learning
- # Statistical Machine Learning
- # Convex Optimization

Programming

- # Distributed System
- # Software Engineering
- # Algorithm Design and Analysis
- # Computer Networks
- # Parallel and Sequential Data
- Structures and Algorithms
- # Introductory to Computer
- System(C) # Machine Learning
- # Principles of O-O Programming
- # Data Mining
- # Rapid Prototyping(JAVA)
- # Numerical Methods
- # Data acquisition
- # Data Management.

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Java

Python

C / C++

JS/ HTML / CSS

Swift

MatLab

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Chinese
English
Japanese

Juncheng (Billy) Li Resume Page 2/2

PUBLICATIONS (citations: 975, h-index: 13)

- Very Deep Convolutional Neural Networks for Raw Waveforms
 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP) 2017, New Orleans, USA
 Wei Dai, Chia Dai, Shuhui Qu, Juncheng Billy Li, Samarjit Das
- ♦ A Comparison of Deep Learning Methods for Environmental Sound Detection
 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP) 2017, New Orleans, USA
 Juncheng Billy Li, Wei Dai, Florian Metze, Shuhui Qu, Samarjit Das
- Real-Time Fine Grained Occupancy Estimation using Depth Sensors on ARM Embedded Platforms IEEE Real-Time and Embedded Technology and Applications Symposium 2017, Pittsburgh, USA Sirajum Munir, Ripudaman Singh Arora, Craig Hesling, Juncheng Billy Li, Jonathan Francis, Charles Shelton, Christopher Martin, Anthony Rowe, Mario Berges
- ♦ Learning Joint Embedding of Video and Text for Cross-Modal Retrieval
 International Conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR) 2018, Yokohama, Japan (BEST PAPER AWARD)
 Niluthpol Mithun, Juncheng Li, Amit Roy-Chowdhury, Florian Metze
- ◆ Towards Zero-shot Learning for Automatic Phonemic Transcription AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence 2020 (acceptance rate: 20.6%), New York Xinjian Li, Siddharth Dalmia, David R Mortensen, Juncheng Li, Alan W Black, Florian Metze
- A comparison of five multiple instance learning pooling functions for sound event detection with weak labeling

IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP) 2019, Brighton, UK Yun Wang, **Juncheng Li**, Florian Metze

- Multiple Instance Deep Learning for Weakly Supervised Small-Footprint Audio Event Detection Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association 2018, India Shaoyen Tseng, Juncheng Billy Li, Florian Metze, Joseph Szurley, Samarjit Das
- Comparing The Max And Noisy-Or Pooling Functions in Multiple Instance Learning For Weakly Supervised Sequence Learning Tasks

Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association 2018, India Yun Wang, **Juncheng Li**, Florian Metze

- On Adversarial Robustness of Large-scale Audio Visual Learning ICASSP 2022, Singapore (BEST STUDENT PAPER AWARD)
 Juncheng B Li, Shuhui Qu, Xinjian Li, Poyao Huang, Florian Metze
- Audio-visual event recognition through the lens of adversary
 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP) 2021, Online
 Juncheng Li, Kaixin Ma, Shuhui Qu, Po-Yao Huang, Florian Metze
- ♦ A Light-weight Multimodal Framework For Improved Environmental Audio Tagging
 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP) 2018, Calgary, Canada
 Juncheng Li, Yun Wang, Joseph Szurley, Florian Metze, Samarjit Das
- Adversarial camera stickers: A physical camera-based attack on deep learning systems International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2019 (acceptance rate 21.8%), Long Beach, USA Juncheng B Li, Frank R Schmidt, J Zico Kolter
- ◆ Universal phone recognition with a multilingual allophone system IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing 2020, Online Xinjian Li, Siddharth Dalmia, Juncheng Li, ..., Graham Neubig, Alan W Black, Florian Metze
- Music Theory Inspired Policy Gradient Method for Piano Music Transcription Neural Information Process System 2018 Workshop on creativity AI, Montreal, Canada Juncheng Li, Shuhui Qu, Yun Wang, Xinjian Li, Samarjit Das, Florian Metze
- ♦ Adversarial Music: Real world Audio Adversary against Wake-word Detection System
 Neural Information Process Sysem (NeurIPS 2019), Vancouver, Canada (SpotLight, top 2.4%)

 Juncheng Li, Shuhui Qu, Xinjian Li, Joseph Szurley, Zico Kolter, Florian Metze